okay so we reached the part where the
angel is talking with the devil and a
guys in mind and she says now I'm going
to give proof to you
of emptiness and after you have learned
them and appreciated them you will for
sure offer to leave this person's mind
and let the Angels take over this
person's mind okay and we're on verse 57
and she the angel goes in two parts she
discusses emptiness in two parts okay
and these are very famous okay one is
called they call it the in Shanti
davidic auntie army which is the idea
that things are made of parts so an army
is made of many individual soldiers and
I can remember you know my a lot of my
Buddhist training was in a small
Mongolian monastery in New Jersey and
there was a very high Lama Cameron which
I guess you know some tartan in and we
spent 25 years in the same house and the
Mongolians were very poor and they built
the temple by themselves and then they
didn't have money so they bought these
really cheap wooden chairs folding
chairs and so I took countless hours of
classes sitting in these chairs which
were torture and ripich's classes were 3
4 hours long and often times with no PP
brain and it was torture to sit in these
chairs you know and I remember he would
always take at the end he would he would
invite everybody to stay for mongolian T
which is baking soda nutmeg salt black
tea milk and
butter and cream in a churn and but you
know after sitting in those chairs for
hours and hours it was like a treat to
go drink the stuff and so I remember
many pleasant conversations with the
other students in the kitchen and one
woman had a you know chin deal all right
so she had a daughter who was six or
something and I remember coming out of
this discussion on parts in the holes
right and I remember going to the
t-brain and talking to Janice you know
this this her mother's name is Carmen
because her mother liked the opera
Carmen and she named her daughter Janice
because she liked Janis Joplin and so
I'm asking Janice you know so are you
your leg and she goes no you know and I
said are you your arm and she goes no
and I say are you all your parts
together and she goes uh-huh and then
I'm like wait the gardener said you're
not yeah and I'm like no you're not she
said well why and I remember that I
couldn't answer her you know so I can't
see this argument without thinking about
her and the point is you can take all
the parts of a car for example and you
can lay them out on the ground and you
can even assemble them but it's not
necessarily the case that you would
recognize it as a car or that you would
see a car right there are many creatures
who don't see a car as a car and
according to Buddhism you would
recognize the final part that every hole
needs is the seed opening in your mind
and a picture coming out and organizing
the parts into a hole you see what I
mean
and until you have that final part all
the conventional parts together are not
the whole thing because not everyone
would recognize all the parts of a car
even if they were put together correctly
there are many beings and in many times
of history that would not recognize it
it wouldn't be a car for them that means
those parts even assembled into a whole
don't make the car ok if it did then an
Eskimo from the thirteenth century would
say oh that's a test line you know but
they don't so there's the final part of
all holes is that your mind must
organize the parts into a thing okay and
different beings with different seeds
have different holes to the same parts
right if the dog sees the parts of a pen
they see something to chew on okay and
that's a gentle proof that the the hole
is also depending on you okay so when
Buddhism says which is verse 57 okay the
next argument she says you are not your
individual parts that's easy you are not
something other than your parts that's
easy but to say you are not all your
parts together is not easy and you have
to understand that thing about the dog
and the human with the pet okay so
that's what Buddhism means when it says
you're not the sum of your parts because
you are not that real some until you add
a perception of all those parts together
an image that comes out of your mind
and organizes all those parts together
that image is planted in your mind by
something kind or something unkind that
you've done to other people
okay got it so your reality is coming
that gluing together of parts in your
life has been done by the goodness or by
the or by their unkindness that you
showed
the people okay so reality is coming
from you okay 57 that's her first
argument to the devil okay and according
to her these arguments are going to
expel a victim from the mind why what if
he's our angry guy
what if he's a guy whose wife is always
yelling at him in the kitchen you see
what I mean
he will enter the kitchen she will yell
at him and he he'll say oh you're just
part arms legs head and the reason I see
a yelling wife is that I yelled at the
kids last week and I planted a yelling
wise scene in my mind and your arms and
legs are just sticks and colors the the
things you say to me are dentals and
sibilants and fricatives they're just
sounds you see then my mind depending on
how I treated the kids last week
organizes them into objects okay so the
parts are not the whole okay so
understanding that the parts are not the
whole is not some philosophical exercise
okay if you know how to use it on a
husband or wife who's yelling at you you
can solve the problem you see you can
correct the problem all right if you
don't understand parts and wholes you
will not be able to if you understand
when your wife or husband yells at you
that the reason you're seeing those
parts together as a yelling person is
that you yelled at somebody last week
right then you will not get angry and
someone will have to leave the apartment
in your head which is yeah the devil
will be forced out okay got it so wisdom
is not just some kind of philosophy it's
something that you're supposed to use in
the kitchen or in your office as the
Colorado Springs the controller and
Treasury boss
you need this kind of knowledge to to
make it fun at work
and to make things go smoothly at work
okay all right mmm so she says you are
not your part you are not their
combination they are not you she covers
all possibilities and then she concludes
and she says you are not you okay she's
talking to the devil all right now
that's a static thing you see that's a
theoretically if time or frozen and all
the parts of the car were sitting there
you could discuss where does the whole
car come from it comes from a seed in
your mind that you planted by what if
the car works it's because you gave
other people rides in the past okay got
it
that's why your mind organizes the parts
into a car that's why you are allowed to
have a car that's working it's only if
you plant the seeds by helping other
people to get somewhere and this is
where cars come from okay they don't
come from Japan factories okay no that's
a devil talk okay that's devil talk and
cars are made in factories
that's devil thought okay cars are not
made in factories cars are made in mines
by people who help other people get
somewhere who need to get somewhere like
refugees on that what do you call that
train the death to anything that the
refugees take from Central America up to
the border and that's where the rest
stop is that we are funding okay they
tend to jump on top and now they're
speeding the train up to see if they can
make it fast enough that people can't
get on top so it's just more people
dying trying to jump on it okay
then having discussed a static object in
time he says the same thing applies to
objects over time okay
the stream of your consciousness today
where you woke up and you had a
meditation here
and then you had a class and then you
had a break that you had some kind of
workshop that you didn't finish my
assignment and then tonight you have
another class okay so you have been you
for I don't know ten twelve hours today
okay
so summer has continued from morning up
to evening so we can also look at why
does she feel like the person in the
morning was her and the person that noon
was her and she still identifies with
the person than evening okay so the idea
of a stream of parts over time is the
second kind of emptiness meditation that
she's proposing to evict him this is his
evicted eviction notice is the emptiness
meditation okay
and she says over time you are also
empty why because over time the moments
of summer in the morning in the moments
of summer in the at noon in the moments
of summer in the evening technically
they are not connected okay there are
discrete moments you know one moment
starts one moment ends and then a new
moment starts and a new moment ends what
glues them together you know people who
get Alzheimer's the glue tends to break
down they can't remember who they were
an hour ago
I I was present at a conversation
between Nick and my the lady that I
helped to help and she used to do her
garden and she's like oh Mickey which I
hate because she has a crush on him and
she doesn't care about me she's 94 you
know and she's Oh Nicky came you know
and she said Nicky you know what are you
up to he said i'm i me and my wife
returned stuff you know i'm blah blah
okay
then like thirty seconds later she said
Oh Nicky you're here what are you up to
and he was patient till the fourth or
fifth time and then he said I just told
you what I've been through
so what happens is you lose the glue you
see the mind stops making images that
glue the you of half an hour ago to the
you of present okay and then people
can't recognize their relatives and
stuff like that okay
the the what he call it the unifying
image that comes out of your mind gets a
weaker with age as the seeds age okay
and then you you forget things and you
can't do things together anymore okay
all right so she's giving those two
arguments to him okay then she says
these are mama hotter who can tell me
what mama hotter
yeah mama means killing yeah like
mortuary or murder okay haha yeah the
verbal route the cognate you're good
okay anyway now she's going to talk
about killing points okay killing point
means in English we say go for the
jugular here right I have a friend he
helped run Roger Pawnee Institute he was
he was a director there he moved to
Hawaii he was making him him and his
wife a new house he tripped on a board a
nail scratched him here and he bled to
death in about five minutes she couldn't
she just stood there watching she can't
do anything this is a Marv mahanta if
you Nick this vein you're dead nothing
can help you you see
so she's identifying mama hottas in him
okay she where she's interested in
killing him is that Buddhist yes in the
case of your misunderstanding in your
mind you are required to be merciless
okay you are looking for jugular points
okay these these emptiness arguments are
meant to Nick the jugular of the devil
in your mind okay and that's on an
hour-to-hour basis I repeat it okay the
purpose of this three-day course
is that you get sensitized
to what your mind is saying all day long
everybody's day is made of two
activities number one getting the things
you want number two
avoiding the things you don't like okay
now all human beings stream of mind the
whole day every thought you have is
aimed at done you either don't want
something or you want something okay and
there's only two ways to get something
okay number one follow the devil's
insane non method okay why is it a bad
method or why is it a non method
competing with others fighting to be
number one
ignoring what others want focus I hate
this book that came out excuse me
watching out for number one or something
like that and it was a New York Times
bestseller liberate yourself be who you
really want to be just tell everybody
else you're too busy to help them and
and and be take care of number one okay
then this is the first option you have
to get things or to avoid things okay
just take care of yourself focus on your
own needs you know you're also one of
the people in the world you're supposed
to help all the people in the world why
not start with yourself and just focus
on that one for the rest of your life
you know this is argument okay so
according to this system you need to
serve another person to plant the seed
you see you cannot plant one of those
karmic seeds which is creating things
around you if you don't have another
person to help I think those of us who
have done through your tree one thing
about through your retreat I don't know
about you guys but it was frustrating
for me that I had to pray all day for
other people but I couldn't do anything
for other people he said I mean and I it
was frustrating to sit there for three
years and plan what I'm gonna do to help
other people
when I got out someone wrote a song
right
yeah guy wrote a song Kong when I get
out
they came on tour with me after three
retreat we went to Johor Bahru Malaysia
there were 1,800 people in the audience
I gave them a five-minute warning that
they were going to sing a song and they
got up and they sing a song called on
what I'm gonna do and I get out and it
sounded like a Johnny Cash Folsom Prison
thing you know and anyway saying there
we're looking for killing points she's
looking for killing points okay and this
is a holy war right
she should destroy the tenants in her
mind which you and I have all day to
think up wrong strategies to get the
things we want and to avoid the things
we don't want okay every strategy normal
strategy that you've ever used in all
the moments of your life were mistaken
they were Devils weren't okay you know I
need I want to break into the movies
right so I should try to find someone
who's a director or you know I should
call my friend or I should check on the
internet and then you spend the whole
day doing that you see and according to
this teaching the only way to break into
the movies would be to help someone else
break into the movies there's a lady
came to me when I was in the diamond
business in New York she begged me for a
job you know and so I tried her for a
day and then I said forget it
you know she wanted to be actress you
know I said but her father wanted her to
work so I I said you know just forget it
you know you're never gonna be a
secretary go try to be an actress you
know
then she's called uma Thurman and her
father always thanks me for telling her
that
okay so 62 the angel before we start off
on
26 wrong ways to do maja murder
meditation emptiness meditation
emptiness of your mind okay
not just any old emptiness every object
has its own emptiness Mahamudra
meditation focuses on the emptiness of
your own mind okay which is the most
powerful kind of emptiness so before she
gets off on 26 wrong Mahmud Ehrman
meditations she talks up the correct one
okay so here's her description all right
so first for about I don't know ten
verses she goes off on on what's a good
Muhammad of meditation
number one the illusion is torn the
rudest ripped out the poison tree is
felled okay and that's a reference to an
ancient city where are you yeah you're
busy you want to talk about killing
points are you shy well you're not shy I
didn't prepare him I didn't warn him
come up here and teach killing points he
translated the text he translated the
ancient book recently do you mind just
like a couple minutes okay
killing points especially trees oh okay
so there's in in the book that I'm
translating there's three examples oh
it's called deathless the book that I'm
translating is called deathless nectar
for helping others it's a class on the
crown of knives and there's three
examples of killing points the first one
is if you're trying to bring down this
big tree you can come at it from
different angles you can have an army of
woodsmen but if you know exactly what
the killing point is you just use a
little metal like a yeah wait a spy it's
called a Spile
it's like a middle
a piece of metal and then you you take
out all the all the essence in the tree
falls on on itself then the second one
is if you're trying to kill an animal
you it's kind of dark but it's it's very
cool you can try to cut the animal at
different points but if you know the
killing point of the animal with just a
little same thing with just a little bit
of effort you find the killing point and
it's it's almost instantaneous and then
the third one is about mechanism that
describes on on the treasure-house of
higher knowledge that there's this whole
mechanism made of both pulleys that you
go in the entrance and there's like
these guards that that have swords and
there's this like a lake with with
sharks and crocodiles and if you know
exactly where the killing point of the
mechanism is you can just throw a wrench
at it and the whole system comes down so
yeah this is a ancient legend about a
king who had a treasure house and he
wanted to protect it so he built all
these nefarious mechanisms including
guys robots with swords and sharks with
metal teeth and they were all hooked up
to a pulley so if you're trying to steal
the gold don't try don't bother to fight
all these guys just go around The Wizard
of Oz curtain and cut the rope that runs
the whole thing you know so the idea is
if you understand that this stuff is
coming from you if the husband who's
coming from you you can cut the unhappy
marriage in about ten minutes you don't
have to go through ten years of struggle
with this guy who is calling you names
negotiating staying up online long
discussions forget it just just plant
some seeds in your own mind help some
who's having trouble with their husband
that will plant seeds in your mind and
your husband will suddenly become
pliable and cooperative and do
everything you want you see so it's
about a ten-minute killing point don't
spend 10 years struggling through a bad
marriage okay the killing point is here
the place to fix the husband is here
without discussion without trouble okay
and that applies to all your other
relationships all right so verse 62 she
says go for the killing point and she
mentions the tree that Sadie mentioned
okay which is a famous palm tree type in
South India and if you drive a spike in
to a certain point in the root system
it'll fall down by itself you know you
know in about a week you see and it's
about the size of a redwood so in those
days it would take about 20 guys a
couple of days to chop it down but if
you know the killing point so the
killing point here is the husband who's
yelling at you is proceeding from seeds
in your mind fix him here and then it's
like a ten minute thing it's a ten
minute fix instead of struggling during
the whole marriage okay it would be so
powerful as a marriage technique
marriage counseling technique right okay
all right if the husband's not coming
from you you should go to a marriage
counselor and you should go through ten
years of therapy okay if he's not coming
from you then you have to do that okay
no choice if he's coming from you stick
a spike here now fix it here in a few
minutes and then so it's all over with
it will fall down by itself okay all
right mmm
then she says if I can stop this devil
which is the state of mind that doesn't
realize that the husband's coming from
me if I can fix him then his extended
family will have to move out also who's
the extended family
jealousy hates
eighty-four thousand variations on
negative emotions you know me and my
brother we used to have an occasional
gang fight when we were in high school
I don't know were you ever there no
we've known each other since we were 17
there's a rule in gang fight you go for
the other leader okay you don't you
ignore all these other guys you just go
for this guy and you punch him in the
head and this is the principle with with
your brain also okay so go for the
misunderstanding of where things are
coming from you knock him down everybody
else has to move out of your apartment
okay got it
are you guys sleepy do you mean what did
you have for dinner thank you I don't
know okay I'll try to be more animated
um let's see by the way the negative
emotions in your mind okay verse 64 they
are destroyable because they never
started they are destroyable because
they never started okay
meaning they never depended on outside
causes and conditions which when present
in the next moment created these
negativities in your mind that's not
where they're coming from they are
coming from past sins
in your mind okay they're not caused by
being hungry or not making enough money
or being a start with they're not caused
by that they're caused by seeds in your
own mind okay you are a witness in your
mind there's somebody talking in your
mind and it's not you why because you
can hear them
what do you mean geshe-la if you can
hear them you're not saying them okay
got in and there's always a time gap
between someone talking and you hearing
okay summer says something to me it
takes so many milliseconds for the sound
waves to hit my ear and by the time I
hear what she's saying she is gone okay
she is gone so who put the negativities
in your mind who's thinking them who's
listening you're listening but if you're
listening you're not talking okay that's
what Veronica always tells me if I
finally figured it out yeah
okay so who's talking in your mind seeds
are talking thoughts are coming out of
karmic seeds in your mind okay according
to what you said to people last week
okay then you planted seeds the karmic
seeds are cracking open every time a
karmic seed cracks open somebody talks
in your mind okay you want to go deeper
when I talk in China everybody's like
back when I talk in America yeah okay
[Applause]
you cannot correct the conversation in
your mind it's not possible this whole
class is a bogus class okay it's not
possible to do it we're talking about it
okay what you hear in your mind is
coming out of a carbon see that was
planning last week
you cannot stop what your mind is saying
now it's too late
my first meditation teacher was a
co-anchor
his big thing was you can't push a tree
back down in the ground you know by the
time you hear the thought the seed is
planted a week ago okay you cannot stop
the devil from talking in your mind it's
not possible am i right no otherwise we
wouldn't be having a class you can
affect how the devil talks next week but
you cannot affect how the
today I don't care if you have shishun I
don't care if you're monitoring your
mind I don't care if you catch your mind
and decide to change the conversation
you cannot okay you are listening to
thoughts that were planted last week
okay you're the victim of your sins okay
this is what she's saying okay he's the
king of negativities and negativities
come out of him okay but those
negativities in your mind never started
okay meaning they were planted last
spring okay
they didn't come up in your mind this
week okay got it you can affect your
state of my next week but you can't
affect it right now if you're depressed
you have to be depressed okay so verse
65 what's the nature of the mind
I mean mahamudra is the meditation on
the nature of the mind what's the nature
of the mind hundred dollar question
we're talking art good Jinyan language
make it cute the nature of the mind is
forgiving you know one day I I asked a
question that depended on the name of my
fifth grade teacher and I bet $3,000 in
Guadalajara right and that guy answered
it I lost 3,000 bucks took me so long to
pay him anyway I've learned if I just go
fast no one can give the answer or if I
pretend I didn't hear it okay the nature
of the mind is that it doesn't have a
nature okay right of its own okay the
nature of the mind is that it does not
have a nature of its own
the only nature that the mind has is to
be a blank slate okay it has no nature
of its own okay it will have whatever
nature you're see to impose on it okay
which are imposed on you by what you did
last week okay and those are imposed on
you by what you did the week before is
it possible to break out of the cycle
yes but only because it's possible to
contradict the devil okay all right
verse 66 my son Julian day from the vada
yogini sadhana $200.00 Muslim Julian
date
come on you did it for three years you
did it for a thousand days but you did
it in English that's why I bet so much
money Masum Julian day means cannot be
expressed in words and cannot be framed
in thought okay and that's this
emptiness the same thing is to describe
what is it how did the translation go
beyond all the outward beyond our words
and thought yeah so she verse 66 she she
quotes this lines to the devil you know
what I'm teaching you is beyond our
words and thoughts okay all right
is it really by the way in Buddhism why
they call emptiness beyond description
it's not that it's beyond description
because Buddhism spent twenty-five
centuries describing it so it's foolish
to say it's beyond description okay if
it's beyond description why is there one
hundred forty one thousand how many
books where's Christina we are
cataloging one hundred eighty five
thousand books right now in Mongolia so
don't tell me no one can describe
emptiness but we can say that when a
person has seen it directly and you talk
to that person they are going to have
trouble communicating to you exactly
what it was okay that's all when they
say emptiness is beyond description
it means a person who has experienced
the direct
I may have trouble describing it to
another person okay it it cannot be
described in a way that the person
listening will be able to understand it
completely it's impossible okay
all right sixty-seven this is the
antidote which fixes itself okay now you
can just skip over those verses there
just sound like these cute little cone
things but it's not true okay that also
has meaning okay
the antidote to our misunderstanding is
these proofs about why a dog looks at a
pen and sees a tutorial right they see
the same parts why don't they see the
same object it proves that some final
part must be coming out of their mind
okay it proves it so if you describe
people if you describe the pen to people
normal people they are misunderstanding
it while you're explaining it okay
because they cannot see directly that
it's coming from their mind got it while
I'm telling while I'm holding up the pen
and I'm describing why it's coming from
you you have a feeling deep in your
heart that it's coming from the pen and
even if I tell you in words what's going
on you cannot at that moment stop
feeling that it's coming from the pen
okay but and so in a sense the words I'm
using you are also misunderstanding them
okay but in time if I keep using those
words you will have a direct perception
of emptiness okay so the antidote is
broken okay the words I used to describe
to you the pen you take to come from me
they are the antidote to your problems
your problems are you think that things
are coming from me while I'm explaining
the antidote to you you think those
words are coming
me got it but the antidote fixes itself
in time if you hear it enough times you
start to realize that gas last words are
coming from you and then if you're a
speaker if you're a public speaker in
the Buddhism business you can point out
that if you don't like something I said
it's coming from you okay if you do like
something I said that's coming from me
okay then you see if people laugh or not
if they don't laughing you didn't
explain it very well
okay now a Carazo
single song one taste right wrote cheek
in Tibetan that's verse 68 she she's
describing really real mood of
meditation before she goes on to 26
different wrong ways to meditate okay
and I think we learned more from the
wrong ways by the way I've suspected
something and I checked there today she
doesn't get to talk after the next few
lines the rest of the book that I
translate I haven't finished it but it's
all the devil talking it's it's
incredible every single one of 26 wrong
emptiness meditations are being
described by the devil and he says it's
so nice people are doing these
meditations it's so wonderful
I'm so safe as long as they keep
meditating like this but then then it's
interesting because the devil corrects
each one okay in the text the devil
corrects he knows what's an emptiness
meditation he doesn't want people doing
it but he points out how they're wrong
okay it's it's kind of intriguing that
it would take the devil to understand
why a meditation is wrong and to correct
it she doesn't get to talk after that he
talks I'm not aware that she has another
line in the whole play
it probably towards the end I would hope
but I'm not sure okay we call single
song anybody want to take a shot for
zero dollars word I learned not to bet
him money why would why would why would
she say a good Muhammad of meditation
the flavor is a single song what single
song mean what does a single song yeah
money yeah money equalness the equalness
of all things what does that mean how's
that yeah all things are equally empty
okay all things are equally not coming
from their side all things are equally
not coming from their side stated
positively all things are equal in
coming from how you treated people last
week okay all things in your world are
equal in coming from how you treated
people last week okay don't complain you
know among a well-trained Buddhist group
which I'm happy to say you are among a
well-trained Buddhist groom there's a
joke
you know somebody says there's this
person who showed up yeah they're the
most irritating person I ever met and
everybody's like why everything's a
mirror right
all things are mirrors you know be
careful when you complain about other
people
if you're sitting among knowledgeable
Buddhists and you complain a lot about
other people they're like yeah that's
right
yeah you're surrounded by incompetence
yeah I understand
okay got it so all things in your life
are equal in that they are coming from
you on a higher level they are equal in
not not
from you okay double negative all things
are equal in not not coming from you
in in Sanskrit a car rasa everything is
the one taste one taste all things have
I translate it as a single song
everything is a single form okay got it
bad things good things devils and angels
both they are the same in one sense they
are coming from you there's no devil
there's no angel you will never mean
who's not coming from you
okay that's emptiness got it like again
you know just to make sure you're not
sleep go like this area what's wrong my
older students have the skill to go like
this every few minutes when they're
totally asleep again
then she says to the State of Mind which
is in a a good Maha mudra meditation
there is no Buddha there is no Dharma
there is no Sangha how can you be there
okay there's no there's no there's no
three jewels you know what you think
you're more important like Buddha's not
there Dharma is not there something
there
but you should be there ignorant okay
like you're more important than the
three jewels what's he mean what do you
mean no Buddha Dharma Sangha yeah when
you're in the direct perception of
emptiness you cannot perceive what we
call deceptive rituals this the physical
symbols of the three jewels statues
temples books okay
the they're called the fake three jewels
okay they're not the real knowledge they
are physical
okay but while you're in the direct
perception emptiness you cannot perceive
a physical event okay it's not possible
okay so don't what do you call it
don't be so what do you call it
Napoleonic complex
illusions of grandeur devil that you
would be there when the three jewels are
not okay got it
don't don't don't have such a high
opinion of your so that you get to be in
a place where the three jewels don't get
the enter which is what the direct
perception of emptiness okay again which
is the Holy Grail and if you get there
your body starts to change into an angel
and you can't stop it okay twenty
minutes just twenty minutes in your life
and you don't have to worry about death
or anything okay just get there all
right mmm now there's a current thing
called jato phe you want to go for a
nick yeah yeah okay good and and she
says don't when you call that don't have
these delusions of grandeur where you
devil believe that you could be in a
human mind during the direct perception
of emptiness okay but what do you think
the next verse says
yeah great Nick said it perfectly was
I'm so glad I didn't bet any money in
the moments in the hours typically I
don't know eight hours ten hours after
the direct perception emptiness you have
these extraordinary experiences okay you
see all living beings in the universe
directly one by one and have feelings of
love for each one okay for example okay
and then during this time is the devil
present in your mind or not if you're
perceiving every living creature human
or not on every planet in the universe
countless planets if you can do that
within half hours time and feel the love
of a mother for each one of them okay is
it even possible in those moments to
have the devil in your mind and we say
yes pieces of him are still there okay
after the direct perception when you
come out you still are making mistakes
okay that's why you got nine more buddy
soft levels to go okay all right mmm-hmm
and she's admitting that in verse
seventy okay
verse 71 unexamined the world is fine if
you don't ask where things are coming
from okay you can you can get to your
day you know things happen and you're
not going to be paralyzed okay but if
you start asking where stuff where does
it come from where's the real I don't
know husband who's yelling at you
the conclusion is he's not there okay
there is no such thing
so unexamined party today can just be
unexamined okay just eat the pizza don't
worry about birth coming from okay
no not okay don't let the devil in your
mind even while you're eating pizza okay
then she says cause and effect is just
the cosmic
play of names anyone want to take a shot
at the names that's close
give it to me better when Buddhism says
the world is a creation of names what
does the word name refer to yeah exactly
it's not verbalizations okay when
Buddhism says the world is a result of
names it's not MiG and word and Phil
okay it's not done in Buddhism the word
name is a code word for the image
luminous image come what do I say
luminous on the day you see those images
you will realize that they have a sort
of a neon character to them okay there
are like lights like a pen image as it
comes out of a comic scene has its own
luminous nature it's a mental nature
okay it's coming out of the mind okay
it's an image of the mind and the mind
is defined as luminous okay which were
coming to later so as a luminous image
comes as karmic seeds crack open and
images come out of parents or people or
yelling husbands okay those images in
Buddhism are called names and they say
everything is just names okay but it's
very confusing okay it doesn't mean
vemana Daniel it doesn't mean it doesn't
mean that okay get used to it okay the
word name in Buddhism when they say
everything is just a product that names
doesn't mean gal say or sureiy or mom
okay
it doesn't mean that it means images
coming out of your mind okay you can
have silence and you're still creating
the world with names got it yeah I got
one knob from guilty congratulations on
becoming suddenly because of the
premature birth of a baby
the director of diamond mountain for the
next six months
[Applause]
[Music]
the former director and his wife had a
baby three months early right I teach he
got off the plane and this thing jumped
out and she's healthy he's healthy he's
fine okay hon Onan he's a to 24 weeks
baby which is just about as fast as you
can do it there's a tradition in
Buddhism that Lord Buddha came out of
his mother's side because it was quicker
and less painful so I have a feeling
Melissa had enough Carmen that it was
something like that okay seriously much
less trouble right OOP all right if you
dig beyond the names verse 73 okay if
you dig beyond the names is there
anything there is there a pen in the
parts of the pen before you think of it
as a pen no okay and that's a famous
Buddhist thing before the name is
applied to the thing the thing is not
what it's named okay means before the
karmic seat cracks open and a unifying
image comes out of the mind then the
parts of a pen are not opinion in the
parts of a car and not acharya okay
that's the final part that's always
needed when you're building a car okay
it's a karmic seed opening soak our
company should what encourage people to
give other people rides because more
cars would be soul I'm talking you know
something we should write a book about
an enlightened world you know what the
kind of weird stuff that would be going
on but you know Toyota would be
encourage you to pick up strangers who
need rides you know so they could sell
more cars okay yeah that'd be nice all
right
mmm now verse 74 until you realize that
the pictures in your mind which we call
names are creating your world trying to
manipulate your world without using
those images
she calls it exhausting she just says
one word who she the angel she says look
until you get it
life is exhausting okay trying to
rearrange objects outside the husband
goes to the marriage counselor you know
yeah like that trying to arrange outside
objects is exhausting fixed the world
here fix the world here is so much
easier it goes so much better okay it
works every time
okay it's not like trying to rearrange
objects outside okay got it
and and the goal of this class is that
in the next few weeks you have a
heightened awareness of the internal
discussion going on your mind I'm gonna
name DCI level 11 and I can't came to me
internal was it called hang on I'm
always trying to think of what's the
next DCI level we do one every year and
it's stressful for me okay I got it
DC I love eleven inner conversations
okay
the subtitle is obvious secret success
technique why obvious secret
huh you listen to your mind all day
every waking moment from the moment you
open your eyes sometimes before you open
your eyes you are listening to your mind
right but you never hear it you see it's
right in front of you how to fix the
world it's right in front of you it's
this far away you could drill in a
quarter inch you know it's that far away
the secret to reality it's always been
that far away the discussion in your own
mind popping out of karmic seeds you
seen I mean the fix for the whole world
is about a quarter inch under your skin
here and you don't know it's been with
you your whole life you see what I mean
so to learn to listen to the
conversation in your own mind it's like
a hidden open sea it's an open secret
maybe I should call it open secret or
obviously good open secrets not sexy
enough obvious means it's in your face
all day and you don't get it okay your
mind is in your face all day but you
don't get it
your mind is creating the world don't
you don't have to go farther than a
quarter-inch in to find solutions for
things you want or things you want to
avoid okay got it you don't have to go
outside okay forget in don't solve
things outside of yourself I'll take
questions later okay okay don't forget
the question but I'm on a roll I am
giving you a break but I want you to
suffer first when I first went to the
monastery it was a refugee camp and we
lived in refugee huts and the teacher
would sit on their bed which was a small
macrame bed and we would sit you know
squash table next to teacher and we were
all crushed in there
in the refugee hut together and it would
start to rain and that the water would
go through them dunk them you know and
it was about 120 degrees and the water
is like spreading on your head and you
have to sit there for four hours you are
not allowed to ask a question you are
not allowed to go peepee and if your
eyes go off the teacher you get whipped
you know and I always said to myself I'm
going to do this to my students when I
get there you know I'm just waiting to
do this okay right word I did it to you
guys they started 6:30 and sometimes
they end at 6:00 okay so what she the
point of verse 74 look it's exhausting
to live your life without understanding
where stuff is coming from it just takes
so much more work you know to send your
husband for counseling blah blah blah
you know get your friends to talk to him
blah blah blah
you know it's so exhausting to do all
this stuff for ten years you know and
then divorce him anyway okay or you
could just fix them here in about ten
minutes okay
and it's so exhausting to do it the
other way who's talking the angel she's
like come on get it straight now here's
her next statement verse 70 fine I'll
give you a break at 8:15 okay 13 more
minutes hang in there try to look
interested all right she says boys were
old men from the day of their birth she
just pops up with this thing okay
suddenly she says she's been convincing
him why he doesn't know anything and
then she says by the way boys have been
old men since the day of their birth
okay and and thinking differently is a
mistake okay to look upon a young child
is to see a person who will die okay to
look upon a nice beautiful baby is to
see a person in the nursing home dying
okay it's the same thing
okay and then you know why does she
suddenly come up with something like
that which is conventional with them and
not emptiness with them yes or not is it
a conventional wisdom to appreciate the
impermanence of life is that emptiness
teaching or not come on you guys are
waffling now see there is a connection
between waffles and meeting waffling
people the same day it seems
conventional but what's one of the
lowest versions of emptiness
impermanence but when you talk about
Antonis you have to talk about something
not being something impossible
that's gotcha that's emptiness what is
impermanence empty ah yeah things that
last forever children who don't die in
nursing homes okay young children
infants who were born this month who
don't die in nursing homes okay
the world is devoid of those that's one
of the emptinesses are in the world it's
a lower emptiness but it's an important
emptiness starchy around when changi
dark would power tuck cheek don't want
him tapa chick ba wait wait that's her
book darpa unchanging chick
Ranjan round one independent yeah that's
the lowest kind of self existent object
okay in Buddhism lowest score okay
what's a non-existent thing in the
lowest school a baby who will not die in
the nursing home okay doesn't exist
gotcha impossible thing emptiness is
empty of that emptiness is empty of that
okay got it
she throws it in to remind you of other
kinds of emptiness okay got it or else
she's a DD which I down okay
then she goes off on some poetry you can
read it okay if you want to make a known
76 77 78 and she compares the emptiness
to the clouds in the sky conditions
convene clouds come together rain comes
down which she calls emptiness okay and
the clouds are illusion and then they
return to the empty sky okay so she's
she goes off on some poetry verse 78 is
same with your body okay she's back to
the kid she's back to the kid your body
comes together like a brief rain what'd
he call
what's a small rainstorm a drizzle or so
I don't know yeah you're the parts of
your body and mind float together almost
serendipity serendipitously and you get
the honor of being alive for a short
time and then they float back to where
they were okay that's all hmm okay I got
four more minutes and I'm gonna use it
if you keep working on Maha muda
meditation you will see how your own
body is the result of seeds opening in
your mind
okay and if you're clever or wise you
can keep making those seeds or you can
adjust your body to a deathless party
okay possible all right which is part of
the goal of Buddhism mmm then verse 80
things do come into your life people you
know your loved ones and people do drift
out of your life okay but it's not
people it's those little images popping
out of your seats okay she's like people
drift into your life you you're allowed
a few years to know them and then karma
tears you apart in in almost in an
economy inevitably almost but it's not
people leaving people
it's images drifting away it's seeds
opening with different images okay she
wants you to understand that loss in
your life is not outside loss is coming
from seeds wearing out that could have
been replenished if you had known how
okay got it
anyone the reflection of the Moon of
wisdom appears in the still water of
emptiness of the mind okay what does it
mean to see emptiness which is the only
thing that can save you the mind has to
be still enough to reflect the image of
emptiness which means you need to learn
conventional meditation techniques okay
you must learn to still the mind to the
to the speed to a slow enough speed that
you can see emptiness okay yeah if you
don't learn to slow the mind and make it
quiet you will never see a karmic seed
open and images come out it's not
possible they are coming out 65 per
second okay if you don't reach deep
state of meditation you can never
observe what I'm talking about the day
you see it directly you don't need me
anymore
I mean not much I also buy refreshments
and stuff but I saw some nice Star of
David cookies at the store and we
brought them tinnitus is a is a holiday
of a Buddhist angel called veggie or
guinea and she's partial to starts of
David's all right you have to eat one
okay I mean I couldn't bring that many I
just you'll have to eat one of the six
points and okay alright anyway verse 81
you have to slow your mind down if you
want to see emptiness Mahmud requires
other more basic meditation skills of
learning to slow down your mind okay
before you get on to content all right
all right don't mistake the don't
mistake the method for the content okay
there's lots of meditations which are
all slowing the mind down so you can
think about nothing which is exactly the
result you get okay when you slow the
mind down enough verse 82 you will be
able to see the images opening in your
mind and you'll be able to see that
things are coming from you and then
you'll be able to see directly how to
fix your husband okay okay
hmm okay one more and we'll take a break
you can't waste your time trying to
solve your problems on the outside but
in the end you're gonna have to deal
with your own sins
okay so you might as well go there now
there's a big thing of in Buddhism about
okay you want to take the slow way go
ahead
do it for five years dude try to fix
your husband for five years or ten years
okay if you really want to I'm not
stopping you but in the end you're gonna
come back to the seats and fix him in a
few in a few weeks okay with your seats
okay
and the nice thing about fixing your
husband with your sins you don't have to
talk to him okay I think that's the best
advertisement for the Buddhist but it's
marriage counseling okay you can fix
your husband without talking to your
husband okay it's like perfect
okay life is perfect all right we're
going to take a 15-minute break when you
come back have some questions ready okay
we'll do questions just to wake you up
if the then when the sugar kicks in
I'll start back on their philosophy
questions
Oh Manny has a question yeah microphone
I promised Manny first first dibs check
one two so it's sort of a follow-up to
the earlier question about you know the
nature of the mind when we talk about
past and future lives in the proof the
one of the what are the assumptions has
to be there's the one about the the
stuff of mind cannot be created
destroyed just like we learned in
physics class in high school so that
stuff my stuff is different than her
stuff is different from your stuff right
it's discrete stuff is that stuff the
same thing that we were talking about
earlier which is the the the Buddha
nature that thing that has always exists
it still exists it sounds like an
unchanging thing but it's stuff which
implies some sort of physicality or
thing okay and so there's a little
confusion I have around
good okay good I like to think of the
mind as a long spaghetti noodle with no
ants and it just keeps going and going
and going and I remember when I was
first learning Buddhism and you know
from my early years with my Lama we're
interesting because he was learning my
culture and I was learning his culture
so we used to have these kind of weird
discussions like he would tell me about
the monkey and the Oprah's who were the
first beings on this planet and I'd say
no it was Adam and Eve and we would have
these cultural clash discussions you
know and then I remember when we were
discussing the beginning of the universe
you know and I was condescendingly
explaining to this person who never saw
bicycle in his life why the people who
invented the airplane were more
intelligent right and why we had it
right and why science was correct and he
said what's the one overriding principle
science that I said wisely from my high
school training all things have causes
you know and then he he talked and
talked and talking you know he was the
best debater out of fifteen thousand
monks in Tibet he got the award he
wasn't a guessing he was a beggar she he
wasn't a Samba Keshi he was an auntie
Dumbo her burger she which means what he
call it he was the best debater out of
fifteen thousand marks so he would set
you up like 15 minutes before you know
it's like a chess player you know he
said oh yeah the science yeah you guys
you know flying steel through the sky
you guys are amazing you're much more
advanced than us you know and then he'd
go on and on and they'd say yeah well so
what was the what was the first thing
how did things start I'd say yeah
everything has to have a beginning you
know and he said well what's that and
I'd say I was the Big Bang you know he
said oh is that the beginning I think
yeah and he said well what caused the
Big Bang I say nothing you know
oh so in the philosophy which says all
things have a cause the the thing that
cost everything doesn't have a cause
yeah that's good yeah and then I'd be
like well what do you think started the
universe and he'd say well obviously
there's no beginning because you can't
have a thing without something to cause
it so that proves that already proves
there's no beginning and that's
comfortable we're comfortable with that
we're not comfortable with you having to
have a big bang that's uncomfortable
there's a little bang before the Big
Bang
No you know so anyway mine according to
Buddhism continues on endlessly
mindstream it has no beginning but it is
it's not physical but it's not emptiness
and there's a basic distinction that we
learn in this I love all seven that the
universe can be divided into positive
things and negative things okay so
emptiness is a negative entity meaning
it's the absence of something okay is
there an elephant between you and me
right now no does that absence exist
yeah if it didn't exist there'd be an
elephant here got it okay so emptiness
is the absence of something okay and and
something like the mind is a positive
entity okay it has awareness it has some
kind of continuation right into it so
emptiness now Buddha nature I think we
didn't quite nail it down Viet V accused
me I'm not nailing it down or I'm not
supposed to say what we say in the car
right okay but you know I can't keep my
mouth shut so she said you know he
didn't really finish the answer to that
guy yeah okay the the Buddha nature in a
person is an absence
okay it is not a positive quality okay
Buddha nature in a person that you have
always had and will always have is the
fact that you don't come from nothing
okay
the fact that you don't not come from
seeds okay got it
so that part of there's only one part of
you which will still be the same after
you get enlightened and that's your
emptiness the fact that you don't come
from nothing okay the fact that you are
not something which is not something
coming from seeds that fact applies to
you from the moment you're born okay
it's not true about vimla at any point
in her life that she is not coming from
seeds okay it is not true about vimla at
any point in her life that her current
condition is not coming from her seats
okay and that is venomous Buddha nature
and because of that fact it is
inevitable that she will become a Buddha
if she's not already okay cool so that's
the difference Buddha nature is a
absence of not not coming from your mind
okay and the mind is a positive entity
it's not physical but it's positive
entity okay its awareness it's
continuing awareness and we'll talk
about it because it's one of the wrong
Maha mudra meditation gets into that
okay other question you I owe you or I
owe him a question in the back
earlier earlier you were talking about
the obvious secret that we have in our
forehead you know and I was curious what
happens when you're aware of that
obviously group yeah I'm good and how
does it affect you know your daily life
and interactions with others yeah good
question well in Buddhism they say neck
so neck so well spoken well spoken from
the moment of our first awareness of
ourselves we are aware of a conversation
in our head right you are listening to
that conversation all day in fact one of
the parts of growing up is when your
mother says don't say everything that's
happening in your head to other people
like don't talk about what you the
conversation you had in the car you know
not everything in your mind and a moment
should be spoken out loud and then you
know that's sort of a milestone in your
childhood when you realize you know you
shouldn't tell your aunt everything is
thinking about it because it might hurt
her feelings I remember the day my mom
said you know you don't have to say
everything you think about your aunt
dear aunt because sometimes it might
hurt her feelings you know so some
things like I can be thought in your
mind but don't express them to everybody
around you and then you start to have an
internal life you start to have an
internal conversation and you start to
draw boundaries between the internal
conversation that you're allowed to
mention and the internal conversation
that you don't mention okay but that
internal conversation itself if you
learn Mahamudra as a meditation
technique means learning to plug into
the internal conversation and watch it
and and evaluate it and then improve it
you see what I mean and in this class
all right all I want you guys to do not
very long just for the rest of your life
okay
plug into the conversation going on in
your mind it's either gonna be you want
something or you want to avoid something
99% of human conversation inside
internal conversation is how do I get
death today and very depressed people I
remember I was shocked I met one of the
wealthiest people in the room and I
became her teacher for a while and she
said some days I don't get out of bed
and I'm like you're one of the
wealthiest people on this planet and you
don't get out of bed for the whole day
she says right I say why she says there
nothing I want to do I have nothing to
do I have nothing no goal I'm depressed
I want to be depressed all day I'm gonna
stand there I never had this problem I
never had enough money to have this
problem I had to get up so anyway if you
get out of bed it's usually because you
want something you want something to
happen that day or you want to avoid
somebody that day and you have to get
out of your house before they come so
you know if you evaluate the discussion
going on in your mind constantly what I
want you to do is just check one thing
you know is this discussion foolish or
intelligent okay foolish means today I
have to do this and this and this to get
this and this and this I have to exhaust
myself by manipulating outside objects
y'all say we'll have to go over there
Dennis will have to go back there Scott
will have to say this and I will control
the outside world and I won't make them
all do what I want you see and then by
the end of the day I'll have what I want
you see that's the devil talking angel
talking is I would like to find someone
that I can serve today so I can plant
the seeds to have what I want tomorrow
happen to me without effort
got it so all I want you to do you know
if you graduate from this class the
certificate is here that you watch your
mind start to get the habit of watching
the internal conversation and see how
much of it is devil talk you see and how
much of it is angel talk that the clue
is angel talk will always be what do I
do for someone else okay what the Chanti
Davis said the devil is the thought of
what shall I do for myself today the
angel is the thought of what can I do
for somebody else today and that's all
that's all angel talk is always gonna be
what can I do for someone else which
inevitably comes back to you and you get
much more than you ever dreamed of and
then double talk is always I want this I
want this you know how am I gonna get it
today okay got it
that's all listen to the conversation
check whether it's angel talker devil
talk and try to reduce the devil tongue
okay devil doesn't mean here evil it
doesn't mean you are you know trying to
kill people or something it doesn't mean
none it means you're not getting what
you want and you are exhausting yourself
in the process
okay got it okay other question one more
question
[Music]
teaching earlier you were saying that
the angel said that over time she's
talking to the devil that you're also
empty because the moments are not
connected and you proceeded to say one
moment ends in one moment begins
according to our eunuch Arjuna though
there is no moment you cannot find an
ending or a beginning so in terms of the
angel
what is she speaking of yeah okay good
I would rather go with the gardener okay
so if you think a moment has ended and
another moment has begun it's because
that line has been drawn by seeds in
your mind that's all yeah that's all
okay it is true that moments end in
moments begin you know we're not having
the afternoon class right now so that
must have ended there must be a line
between them but that line is imposed by
your names right which are pictures
coming from your mind okay so we accept
time but only in a nominal sense meaning
only in a name sense meaning the images
in your mind have drawn the line between
the past and the future past in the
present but that line is fluid right
depending on different people's seeds
okay all right I want to go ahead a
little bit because it gets sexy and if
we don't reach the sexy part it's kind
of sad all right
83 you can keep trying to manipulate the
outside world you will exhaust your
stuff okay stop trying 84 I like it she
says by the way mr. devil any knowledge
you gained from my talking to you has
come from you okay and that's kind of
cool that the angel will tell the devil
that the person responsible for their
angel is the devil it's probably the
worst thing you can tell a double to
tell them all the angels are coming from
you okay so she's like the teachings on
emptiness are in echo okay you are
getting back the wisdom which you gave
to others in the past okay got it she
she makes the point it's kind of a
modest point to make right she's like
mr. devil if you understand anything
from hour-long conversation the only
person you have to give credit to is
yourself okay you created me
okay that's kind of poignant feels like
to me that the angel is giving the devil
credit for her existence okay all right
85 because the causes and conditions are
complete emptiness sings back to you
like an echo okay
you created this emptiness teachings mr.
devil okay and when you start a
emptiness in the coming days by watching
your mind
and reading the poem right just keep
being aware that you wrote the book okay
she says all right now she says I hate
to say it but there's no one place in
the universe where you and I could stay
together okay forget the human mind I'm
not just talking the human mind okay
the way it's called Zen dungee or the
way you hold things to be and the way I
hope things to be are opposite so we
cannot coexist she's against coexistence
she's a nationalist and not a globalist
okay I got my country you got your
country you know one of us benefits and
one of us I'm has to be a loser and it's
gonna be you okay so I don't know if
you've ever heard that kind of thing but
uh she's that's her position and also I
hate this she's like either you're gonna
stand this mine or I'm gonna stand this
mine okay but we can't both stay this
town is not big enough for both of us
and that's her repeated assertion now 88
the devil responds 89 you keep blah blah
miss angel you're like Miss blah blah
you know you're blah blah blah
philosophy philosophy philosophy blah
blah blah you blah blah
I do think okay you talk you're a talker
I'm a doer what do you do I provide the
eight worldly thoughts to everybody okay
like I'm a doer okay I don't talk
philosophy I'm a supplier of useful
things okay the eight worldly thoughts
okay they're called jig Dench again
right
I went and got them for you from no no
no gardener okay they're in the gardener
okay in his letter to the king okay
so her lekha in sanskrit su
means good right heard means heart hurt
changes to hurl before lekha sue her all
vector mecca means well-written okay let
her to a heart friend okay and in there
and the gardener in a poem lists the
eight worldly dumbest okay so I thought
we would just mention them since who's
taking credit
yeah the devil's like you talk I do okay
well what do you do I provide the eight
worldly thoughts to everybody or what
are they okay here it is G technique
Ichi Guinea me she thanked him
by G thank Emma means knower of the
world and it's a way to address a king
two thousand years ago look of it you
know you wise one okay because it was
common for for Saints to advise kings in
those days okay Nana money okay
worried about what you get and worried
that you lose something is two of the
eight attitudes supplied by the devil I
don't talk I do I give people these two
attitudes okay based on believing that
things are not coming from you you can
worry about getting stuff or not getting
stuff if you know it's coming from you
you
just plant the seeds and you don't have
to worry about it okay it'll come I like
to tell the story I went to Dharma
Madras yoga class it's just to our class
it's a special suffering class and I
went for two hours and this guy's hard
and and when I was leaving someone
handed me an envelope you how to check
in it for $100,000 I never met this
person before you know and I'm like who
are you are you don't know me why are
you giving me this money I also don't
know I just felt like I should give it
to you you know no and that's how we
built the water David stump built the
water system five kilometres of water
system at Diamond Mountain Retreat
Centre and with this money okay and the
guy just hand it to me okay so you don't
have to worry about am I gonna get money
or am i'm not gonna get money don't
worry about it how much should we got
this morning ninety four thousand
dollars I was bragging yesterday pelops
money and then this morning we got
ninety four thousand no this afternoon
this morning we got anyway just plant
the seeds and people send your checks
okay got it you get emails jig me that
email today sooo gum it's ninety four
thousand thought what we gonna do take
it I I agree
okay Nana my way
naina money don't worry about getting
things and not getting things just plant
seeds and relax things will come emails
will come ok new day Tommy day Damien
mean day means then yeah don't get so
freaked out if you don't feel well today
ok don't get so freaked out if you
temporarily do feel well today they will
both pass okay so don't get so excited
when you have a good day and don't get
so depressed when you have better it's
gonna pass anyway you know just calm
down plant good seeds okay
so those are the third and fourth
worldly thoughts you know five and six
yen Dominion yen means guilty what
yeah people speak good about you on the
Internet
okay oh he's such a nice guy you know
for every what do you get what do you
call that evaluation on the Internet
what yeah for every bad really good with
you on the you get on the Internet trust
me you'll get a bad one don't worry
don't don't let yourself when you can't
esteem be determined by what you read on
the internet about yourself okay just
let it go okay if you're a good person
then be happy if you're not a good
person then be a good person but don't
get so concerned about what people write
okay yen Dominion means don't don't
spend your time thinking about it okay
then it says a third of mapa personally
to your face people say oh you're so
you're so nice
you're such a good teacher you know
you're so handsome and then other people
behind your back say he's so stupid and
he he's boring and he's got a bald spot
and just let it go just you know be be
happy with this so okay alright having
those eight attitudes is the devil's has
supplied those eight okay he claims that
he's not a talker he's a doer which is
probably true all right then he says
okay verse ninety and we got one more
minute let me do I'm almost done I am
Mount Meru you are something of a moment
who's talking yeah Mount Meru is the
central mountain of the universe it's
like the Everest okay it doesn't move it
stays in one place where the human mind
okay I am Mount Meru mo immoveable you
are like you know a flea crawling across
the floor okay alright you are a flash
of lightning I am the Great Salt sea
okay according to Buddhism the world is
encircled by a a great salt sea that
never moves right and you're like a
flash of lightning you are a blink of an
eye I am a mother's love for her child
meaning you love yourself like a mother
loves her child when when ignorance is
in your mind when you don't understand
where things are coming from you have a
self love which is unshakable a
destructive self love which is
unshakable and you know just for a fact
she compares it to the love of a mother
for a child which is a pure love which
is a good love okay got it
all right then now one more one more
line okay
93 okay
the devil says some people say they will
meditate and by doing the meditation
they will drive me out of the mind and
they say quote I will meditate on the
mind as it really is okay
it's a segue to what yeah now you're
gonna get all the Mohammed or meditation
versions okay and for me it's just like
visiting 26 yoga studios and listening
to the ridiculous meditations frankly
and mostly ridiculous visa become
unerring I mean you're gonna take you
he's gonna take you on a tour of 26
ridiculous meditations okay that maybe
they're nice maybe they make you feel
good for
and and you will die anyway
okay got it all right so how do we segue
into that the devil says some people say
they're gonna kick me out and she says
oh really how and he says they're gonna
meditate and kick me out
Oh what kind of meditation on the true
nature of the mind okay which is Maha
mudra okay so now we get to the crux of
the text okay got it now he's setting
you up
the devil is sending you on okay some
people say they're gonna get rid of me
with a meditation and then throughout
this next session he's gonna say Kaylin
name came an $800 close but no cigar
came with Nick come on don't get it's a
it's it says it's a joke
caramel means a joke okay it's the
ancient it's 2,000 years old word for
it's a goddamn joke you know they're
gonna kick me out of mine
yeah yeah listen to the meditations
they're gonna tear you know you won't
believe it you know he's like he says I
will dance on their brains you know I
love these meditations you know
close your eyes don't think about
anything he says I love that one I'm
dancing on that lady's praying you know
and he keeps bragging about how pleasant
it is for him to stay in a human mind
when they're doing this stupid
meditations you know watch your thoughts
go through your mind don't try to just
stop them
don't try to close your eyes focus on
the black at the back of your eyelids
you know try to think about nothing you
know like that
there's no good there's no bad someone
kisses you don't smile someone punches
you don't scowl you know all this stuff
you know and he's like after each one
he's gonna say and I continue my memory
dance
in their mind okay he's bragging about
what fertile soil it is for him in the
mind of most meditators gotten depressed
yet okay so we're gonna learn by default
that's what the word I was looking for
him by default we will learn what's a
correct meditation because he will teach
us 26 wrong ones that he likes that that
he enjoys okay because they don't he
says he says no like me John
no I mean yeah they don't lay a finger
on me he said okay these 26
these are nice meditations why because
the devil can just sit there and they're
like you know he's like my nice to be
here okay so 26 meditations that don't
hurt at all the negative side of your
mind
okay got it so we'll start that
depressing trip tomorrow okay
don't forget your workshop tomorrow and
tomorrow evening 3 to 5 is it part of
the evening we'll have we would like to
have what do you call it
like we'd like to get you have you come
up and entertain the rest of us with an
angel devil conversation but it must be
relevant to your real life ok to your
current real life if you're working at
Colorado Springs government offices and
they just hired some idiot from New York
City who's bothering you this week then
let that be the subject of your angel
devil talk you know angels like oh I
heard you had trouble at your office
Devils like yeah I got this guy from New
York on my ass you know
and then angels like well wedding and
what's the problem devil he's always
criticizing the work I do and he says I
don't produce it
you know and then ain't just like well
what are you gonna do about that and
devils like I gotta have a talk with the
supervisor you know we got to talk
heart-to-heart
I gotta inform him about this guy cuz
every time the guy talks to the
supervisor he acts intelligent and
sensitive and then when he's along with
me he's like a creep you know I gotta
talk to the supervisor I'm thinking to
record him on my iPhone you know and
bust him you know and then angels like
gee you know he sounds really bad
probably you've never done anything like
that right
okay and then he says and then she no
I've never done anything I really have
not done anything like that yeah but do
you think you've never done any small
thing that might have grown into this
thing okay that we want some drama
tomorrow okay we want subtlety okay
demons are subtle okay don't have this
conversation like wow you don't know
it's coming from you oh I thought it's
coming for me
no it's coming for you okay thank you
okay we don't want something like that
you know we want a little rasa we want
some excitement okay we want some drama
you know we want to know we're quite not
clear who's gonna win the argument and
the devil has to be intelligent and
sophisticated okay because they are
Devils are not people who wear horns
they're people wearing GQ killers who
show up in your life and convince you
that you should spend your time you know
investing or something
okay got it so I don't want to see any
stupid Devils tomorrow I want to see
super intelligent Devils and slightly
more intelligent angels okay got it and
make it cool make it something creative
okay got it
and I'm looking forward to listening to
them are we good